<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-16T15:35:30-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Will Parker’s Website</title><entry><title type="html">Stoicism - My initial understanding</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/16/Stoicism-Initial-Understanding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stoicism - My initial understanding" /><published>2021-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/16/Stoicism-Initial-Understanding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/16/Stoicism-Initial-Understanding.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I’m doing here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stoicism seems to be all the rage these days. Though the contrarian in me wants to steer clear of what seems like just a philosophical fad of our time, most bits of Stoicism I’ve come across have resonated with me. And I’ve decided to do a deeper dive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been soaking in all I can from online stoic resources–podcasts, blogs, youtube channels–and I’m about to read Letters From a Stoic by &lt;a href=&quot;https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/seneca/&quot;&gt;Seneca&lt;/a&gt;. I’m taking the time now to summarize Stoicism from a distance so that I can see how my understanding of it changes as I read the thoughts of the stoics themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stoicism, at a glance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can summarize the basics into three main takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s a Life Code&lt;/strong&gt;. The Stoics weren’t just a bunch of guys sitting around and coming up with ideas about what &lt;em&gt;would be&lt;/em&gt; a proper way to live. For them, it’s about actually doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Waste no more time arguing what a good man should be. Be One.” –
Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Stoicism isn’t a philosophical model for deducing nitty-gritty logic
problems or for judging actions, laws, and people in hindsight. It’s
more of a code for how to live.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s a main goal:&lt;/strong&gt; figure out what is in your control and don’t let anything else 
 	affect you. Stoics emphasize that the most notable things that are out of your control are those which the average person spends an &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; large amount of time thinking about: the future and the past.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are 4 primary virtues.&lt;/strong&gt; In their eyes, these virtues should dictate how you make decisions in situations that &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; in your control.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wisdom:&lt;/strong&gt; An understanding of what is a matter of moral importance and what is uncontrollable and thus meaningless. It is grown over time and used practically.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courage:&lt;/strong&gt; The will and resilience to use your wisdom, especially when the crowd pressures you otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperance:&lt;/strong&gt; Having at most what is enough and not depriving yourself of less than what is essential. Refers to anything–comfort, pleasure, responsibility, friends, challenges, free time…&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justice:&lt;/strong&gt; Marcus Aurelius put it best and simply: “thought and action resulting in common good”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Learn more&lt;/strong&gt;
Here are some resources I used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dailystoic.com/podcast/&quot;&gt;Daily Stoic Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.holstee.com/blogs/mindful-matter/stoicism-101-everything-you-wanted-to-know-about-stoicism-stoic-philosophy-and-the-stoics&quot;&gt;Good in-depth blog post: ‘Stoicism 101’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9OCA6UFE-0&quot;&gt;TED-Ed: Cool animated intro to Stoicism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What I’m doing here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adding a Blog to my Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/12/adding-a-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adding a Blog to my Site" /><published>2021-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/12/adding-a-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/12/adding-a-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m adding a blog to my site to encourage myself to dig deeper and more formally into my interests. Currently, I’m an avid journaler. Unfortunately when journaling I fall too often into the traps of messy thoughts and lazy language. I figure that by posting my thoughts publicly–despite my incoming 0 pageviews–I’ll be forced to write things I’m a little more proud of. Which is a really exciting prospect for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows, maybe if I do something with my life somebody will actually read this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m adding a blog to my site to encourage myself to dig deeper and more formally into my interests. Currently, I’m an avid journaler. Unfortunately when journaling I fall too often into the traps of messy thoughts and lazy language. I figure that by posting my thoughts publicly–despite my incoming 0 pageviews–I’ll be forced to write things I’m a little more proud of. Which is a really exciting prospect for me.</summary></entry></feed>